LAUREN CASTAGNI MOTE

STRATEGY LEADER



CONTACT

1 07507 463 167

✓ laurencastagnimote@gmail.com

2 York, UK

SKILLS

- 4 C's Research Methodology
- Audience Definition & Segmentation
- Brand Activation
- Brand Experience
- Brand Strategy
- Creative & Campaign Strategy
- Ideation & Innovation
- Team Building & Leadership

EDUCATION

BA POPULAR MUSIC PRODUCTION

The University of Huddersfield

2011 - 2014

A LEVELS

Woking College, Surrey

2008 - 2010

GCSE'S

George Abbot School, Surrey

2003 - 2008

PROFILE

I'm a results driven strategic and creative thinker, with a proven ability to lead and motivate others to deliver exceptional creative campaigns and impactful brand projects across a range of sectors, from entertainment and FMCG to finance and retail.

EXPERIENCE

SENIOR HEAD OF INSIGHT & STRATEGY

FNJOY - Leeds

2023 - Present

A leadership team role, responsible for reshaping our strategic approach to drive more effective campaigns for our clients. Key accounts include: Valspar, Ronseal, V&CO, Brompton, Camira Fabrics, House of Rohl and AgeCo.

CO-FOUNDER

LAUREL BRANDS - London/Leeds

2021 - Present

Laurel Brands is a venture studio and brand consultancy that works with brave businesses to help them unlock and accelerate their next stage of growth.

HEAD OF INTEGRATED STRATEGY

LIVE & BREATHE - London/Leeds/Amsterdam

2021 - 2022

I worked across a range of international client accounts, including: Heinz, 1664 Blanc, Carlsberg, Dufry (World Duty Free), Nestlé, Imperial Brands and Morrisons.

SENIOR PLANNER

HOME / IMA HOME - Leeds

2019 - 2021

Key clients included: Novuna, Royal Canin, Mars, Aviva, 32Red, Dr. Oetker Baking and Jet2. I was interim Head of Planning for 10 months.

LAUREN CASTAGNI MOTE

STRATEGY LEADER



ABOUT ME

In my spare time I run a record label and a brand consultancy that works with early stage start up businesses.

I'm an F1 spectator and avid Liverpool supporter, who treats the management of my FPL team like it's a second job. I also make a great Negroni (among an array of other cocktails - one good thing to come out of lockdown!). The most recent addition to my bucket list is to participate in the all-female classic car *Rallye des Princesses* - watch this space!

I am a dual national, holding both Australian and British passports.

EXPERIENCE CONT.

FREELANCE MARKETING & BRAND CONSULTANT

York/London

2018 - 2019

Head of Brand - Kyra TV

- I developed the marketing and brand strategy for a new business unit that included brand and merchandise development
- I worked with the company's influencers, creative and production teams, as well as freelance designers on several brand propositions and launches
- During this period I was responsible for forecasting and managing a multi-million pound budget and P&L

Head of Marketing - Gear4Music

- I managed a department of over thirty people across seven teams whilst the Director of eCommerce was on secondment
- During my tenure I developed a multi-channel, twelve month marketing strategy and content plan

SENIOR MARKETING MANAGER

UNIVERSAL MUSIC GROUP - London

2014 - 2018

- I managed relationships with key stakeholders (managers, artists, labels, agents) and coordinated various teams to deliver projects and campaigns with consistently high results, while maintaining a top level fan experience
- The above included marketing strategies for numerous high profile album pre-order campaigns, including fifteen UK #1 albums for artists such as Sam Smith, Take That, Ariana Grande, The 1975, Florence + The Machine, Mumford & Sons and The
- Hiring of the majority of the ten-person team I co-managed
- Development of product offerings and direct to fan marketing activations (including
 offline events/pop-up's), with a focus on increasing average basket values and chart
 eligible music sales
- Brand management for artists like The Rolling Stones and The Weeknd